http://www.sor.org/privacy-statement

Nuclear medicine hints and tips
Personal protective equipment (PPE)
Pregnancy
Pre-registration education providers
Radiotherapy services
Returners to practice; retired radiographers; registered radiographers in other work areas; and volunteers
Students
Wellbeing, emotional and mental health support and resources
Where can I find information about the imaging appearances of Covid-19?
Patient Advisory Group
Meet the Patient Advisory Group (PAG)
Working in the UK
The Imaging Services Accreditation Scheme (ISAS)
MoA, AoA & handbook
Comprehensive Spending Review (CSR)
Legal reports & accounts
SoR pension Scheme Statement of Investment Principles
The College of Radiographers
College Board of Trustees
What is the impact of the College of Radiographers?
A Manifesto for Tomorrow’s NHS
General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
Help and advice
How do I donate to the Benevolent Fund?
CoR events
Developing tomorrow’s leaders: Essential Training for Radiography Managers
Policy & guidance document library
Archived and superseded policy and guidance document library
Useful links & resources
Developing Tomorrow’s Leaders: Essential Training for Radiography Managers, March 2020
Research Resource Articles
Council for Allied Health Professions Research (CAHPR)
Log of live member research
Research Specialist Interest Groups
Formal Radiography Research Mentorship (FoRRM)
External Assessors
Professional expert (expert witness)
North West chest x-ray reporting radiographers SIG
Diagnostic Imaging Advisory Group (DIAG)
Educational Resources
The Control of Electro Magnetic Fields at Work Regulations (CEMFAW)
News
Nuclear Medicine & Molecular Imaging Advisory Group (NMMAG)
ADC 2013
Problem at work?
Carrying out a Risk Assessment
Gender Occupational health and safety (GOSH)
Introduction
In this Privacy Policy, "We", "Us" and "Our" mean the Society of Radiographers Limited, registered in England and Wales, company number 00169483 and the College of Radiographers, registered in England Wales, company number 01287383. Our registered office is 207 Providence Square, Mill Street, London SE1 2EW.
We are firmly committed to protecting your privacy and aim to be clear when we collect your information and use it only as you would reasonably expect.
How we use personal information
We will not use your personal information unless we have first told you how we will use it or it is obvious how we will use it.
We collect and use personal information for:
Membership applications for all types of membership
Membership administration including but not limited to: payment, renewals, providing event information, delivery of CPD, campaigning, keeping a record of our relationship with a member
Membership benefit administration is by post, telephone, and electronic means
Representation of the whole membership, a workplace group or individual
Elections and appointments to committees
Processing nominations and making awards
Personal injury claims and indemnity insurance
Processing and administering Benevolent Fund (ICO registration number Z9185794) applications and donations
Processing and administering student records
Event applications, registrations and administration
Informing people about our events
Carrying out surveys of members
Forwarding member surveys and consultations run by other organisations with whom we collaborate or are funding
Processing grant applications and awards
Processing applications for and maintaining a public voluntary register of sonographers
Processing accreditation of assistant practitioners
Processing member expenses
Employee administration
Our legal basis for processing personal information
The Society of Radiographers and the College of Radiographers share all personal information that is processed. Our lawful basis for the purposes that we process personal information is consent, for the performance of a contract, or for our legitimate interests.
The law allows us to collect and use personal data if it is necessary for our legitimate business interest and so long as its use is fair, balanced and does not unduly impact your rights. In many situations, the best approach for our members is to process personal data because of our legitimate interests, rather than consent.
We will ask for your consent to send you marketing emails and text messages. You can withdraw consent for this at any time.
Usually we will only process sensitive personal data if we have your explicit consent. In extreme situations, we may share your personal details with the emergency services if we believe it is in your ‘vital interests’ to do so. For example, if someone is taken ill during one of our events.
We may also share your personal information where we are compelled by law to do so.
We process employee personal information to meet our legal obligations as an employer.
How we collect personal information
We collect personal information from you directly through our website, through surveys and sometimes paper forms.
Universities may provide us with your personal information when they register you for student membership with us. We may share your information with your University in administering your SoR membership or your University student record.
We may collect information about the software on your computer (your browser version etc.) and your IP address (your connection with the internet) to improve your interaction with the Website and for our records.  This may happen automatically without your being aware of it.
We may use cookies (small text files which we and other website operators store on your computer when you visit our websites) to deliver a better and more personalised interaction. They enable us to recognise you when you return to the Website, store information about your preferences, and improve the way your searches are processed.  They also enable us to generate statistics about the number of visitors we have and how they use the Website and the internet.  You can set your browser to reject our cookies if you wish (you should consult your browser help section for details), but this might restrict your use of the website and other websites. For more information about cookies, please see our cookies statement.
The personal information that we collect
The type and quantity of information we collect and how we use it depends on why you are providing it.
For membership applications, administration and renewals we will collect:
Your name
Your contact details
Your date of birth
Details of your HCPC registration
Your place of work and job title
Your pay and hours worked
Information about your specialities
Information about your qualifications
Your mailing preferences
Your bank or credit card details
Your gender, nationality, ethnicity, and if you have a disability. We make it clear that providing this information is optional. If provided it is used for equal opportunities monitoring.
In addition to the personal information that is needed for membership applications, renewals and administration, we may collect other personal information as follows.
For whole membership, workplace group or individual representation we may also collect:
Work place name, address and contact information
For elections and appointments to committees we may also collect:
Qualifications, training and employment history
For processing nominations and making awards we may also collect:
Some personal circumstance information
Name and contact details of the nominee
For personal injury claims and indemnity insurance we may also collect:
Medical records and circumstances surrounding claims information
For processing and administering benevolent fund applications and donations we may also collect:
Financial records and information
Medical records and information
For event applications, registrations and administration we may also collect:
Source of referral
Medical information such as dietary requirements and any disabilities relevant to accommodating event attendance
For informing people about our events we may also collect:
Names and contact details of non-members
For carrying out surveys of members we may also collect:
Employer information
For processing grant applications and awards we may also collect:
Employment history
Education and training
Referee name and contact details
For processing applications for and maintaining a public voluntary register of ultra-sonographers we may also collect:
Details of any relevant registration
For processing accreditation of assistant practitioners, we may also collect:
Employment history
Education and training
Referee name and contact details
For processing member expenses, we may also collect:
Financial records and information
How we may share personal information
We may share some of your personal information with organisations that carry out processing operations on our behalf, such as web services companies and mailing organisations. We carry out checks on these companies before we work with them and put a contract in place that sets out our expectations and requirements, especially regarding how they manage the personal information that we give to them.
We do not sell or share personal information to third parties for the purposes of marketing.  But, if we run an event in partnership with another named organisation your details may need to be shared with them. We will be very clear what will happen to your personal information if you register for such an event.
We may share some personal information with the Electoral Reform Society in the event of an election or a ballot.
Members' contact details, including email addresses, may be shared with SCoR volunteers such as accredited representatives and committee members to aid communication between members and interest groups.
We will not sell personal information other than as part of a sale of a substantial part of our assets. We may disclose it to a prospective purchaser, but only for use in connection with that sale.
We may need to disclose your details if required to the police, regulatory bodies or legal advisors.
We may need to make our list of membership available for the Personal Indemnity Insurance.
We may share some personal information with third-party market researchers to help us understand member views and improve our services. Your participation is always gratefully received but not mandated and you are welcome to decline taking part. We will not share your personal information directly with academic researchers but you may see invitations to participate in existing SCoR communications channels. Again participation is always gratefully received but is not mandated.
We may need to share your personal information with your employer and their appointed third-parties (e.g. solicitors) in accordance with accepted practices in trade union representation.
We will only ever share your data in other circumstances if we have your explicit and informed consent.
It may sometimes be necessary to transfer personal information overseas. Any transfers made will be in compliance with data protection regulation.
How we protect personal information
We undertake regular reviews of who has access to information that we hold to ensure that your information is only accessible by appropriately trained staff, volunteers and contractors.
We provide guidance and regular data protection training to our staff.
We ensure that there are appropriate technical controls in place to protect your personal details.  For example, our computer network and servers are protected and routinely monitored.
We store all personal information that you supply us with on secured servers or in secure paper files. For your protection, any payment details that you provide us with will be encrypted using SSL (Secure Sockets Layers) technology.
Unfortunately, the transmission of information over the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to ensure that your personal information is protected, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the website. Any transmission of your personal information by you is therefore at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try and prevent unauthorised access.
How long we keep personal information
We will only keep personal information for as long as we have a valid reason for keeping it. After that we delete or dispose of the information securely.
We keep personal information about:
Our membership indefinitely so that we can administer and prove membership. Non-core information (e.g. personal details not relevant to prove membership at any point in time) about members is destroyed ten years after membership has lapsed.
Representation case data of an individual are held for 3 years from resolution of case.  Summary data of the case are held on indefinitely as a record of activity.
Elections and appointment to committees indefinitely to maintain a record and history of committee members.
Award recipients indefinitely, and all nominations for five years for our records.
Personal injury claims for 3 years after settlement has been made to maintain a record that a claim was made and of the results.
Benevolent fund applications for 5 years after applications are made so that we can identify repeat applications to the fund.
Event applications, registrations and administration for 2 years until after the event has taken place.
Surveys of members for 3 years after the survey so that data can be referenced for statistical analysis.
Grant applications and awards indefinitely for successful applications and persons to abide by company rules.
The public voluntary register of sonographers (PVRS) for 2 years after successful application as the register is updated every 2 years.
Accreditation of assistant practitioners for 2 years after application has been approved or deferred to delivery professional service
Member’s expenses for 6 years as required by law.
Employees for the duration of their employment and 6 years after employment ceases in accordance with the law.
Your rights
You have a right to know what personal data we hold, who we acquired it from, how we process it, the logic involved in any automatic processing, and who we disclose it to.
You have a right to ask us not to process your personal data for direct marketing purposes unrelated to SoR membership.
You have a right to ask us not to make decisions based solely on the automatic processing of your personal information.
You have a right to ask us not to process your personal information in a way that is likely to cause unwarranted and substantial damage or distress.
You have a right to ask us to erase your personal information.
These statutory rights are qualified by exceptions and exemptions.
To exercise any of these rights, please contact us using the address below.
You can find out more about your rights from the Information Commissioner, who regulates data protection and privacy.
Changes to this policy
We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.  If we make any significant changes in the way we treat your personal information we will make this clear on our website or by contacting you directly.
Contact
Please feel free to contact us with any questions, comments or queries regarding this Privacy Policy. All questions should be directed to the Data Protection Officer at the Society and College of Radiographers at 207 Providence Square, Mill Street, London SE1 2EW, dpo@sor.org.
Printer-friendly version
Content tools
Printer-friendly version
Contact us about this page
Email to a friend
Tweet
Style Switcher
Small Font|font
